ILGWU. Jay Mazur papers, 5780/203
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series II. Subject files
  - International Textile, Garment, and Leather Workers' Federation (ITGLWF), 5th World Congress, September 26-30, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    See also Textile; see also NAFTA; see also Globalization Agenda; changes to ITGLWF Rules; reports of affiliated member nations; list of new members of the Presidium and Executive Committee; speeches by Mazur: remarks on the trade resolution and country report
  - International Textile, Garment, and Leather Workers' Federation (ITGLWF), 1987-1988 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    Letters from Mazur to the executive directors of AFL-CIO international labor divisions (AIFLD, AAFLI, African-American Labor Center) with attached description, "Health & Safety: A Programme for the 1990's," Fifth World Congress, Tokyo, 26-30 September 1988, and recommendation by ILGWU to appoint Eric Bombart as research assistant to the project, description of duties, request for funds committed to project, December 12, 1988; rules of the organization; nominations for membership on Presidium and Executive Committee, correspondence re representation of ILGWU; conference agendas, draft resolutions; memos re proposals to reorganize Executive Committee and Presidium to represent less developed countries; correspondence with Zensen (Japanese Federation of Textile, Garment, Chemical, Mercantile and Allied Industry Workers' Unions); memo from ILGWU international relations assistant director Michele Briones to Mazur re agenda item re dues, political infighting; minutes of the Presidium, Feb. 26-27, 1987; correspondence and charts listing dues from member countries
  - International Textile, Garment, and Leather Workers' Federation (ITGLWF), 1986-1987 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    Report by the Education Secretary on several African and Asian countries, noting decision not to develop any new projects with Latin America until differences with FITITVC have been resolved; agenda for Aug. 30-31, 1987, Presidium meeting and draft minutes of Feb. 26-27, 1987, meeting; minutes of Aug. 30-31, 1987, meeting; applications for general secretary from eight members of different nationalities; draft of ITGLWF World Action Programme re human rights, wages, GATT, etc., Aug. 30-31, 1987; survey on hourly wages in the textile industry of member nations, 1985-86, comparison since 1980, with narrative analysis; draft protocol for renewal of the Multifiber Arrangement, sent to all affiliates; handwritten notes by Mazur
  - Japan, 1990-1994 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    Letter to Mazur from the U.S. Counselor for Labor Affairs, U.S. Embassy in Japan, with enclosed article from Japan Economic Journal (January 28, 1991) about a coat-making robot, January 24, 1991; article from Harvard Business Review (September-October 1990), "Political Advantage: Japan's Campaign for America," with cover letter from Mazur to Bobbi Sutton, Vandalia, MO, October 5, 1990; article from Cornell Enterprise (business school), "How the Game Is Played in Japan," summer/fall 1990; joint statement: Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union, International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, ZENSEN, 8th Joint Conference, 12-14 December 1994; routine correspondence
  - Japan imports, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    List of estimated apparel production, imports and import penetration valued in equivalent current U.S. dollars for every year 1968-1986
  - Japan Institute of Labor, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    See also Zensen Drafts of address by Richard Rumelt, assistant director, ILGWU New England Region, to the JIL Prospective Trade Union Leaders Invitation Program; related correspondence
  - Jewish Labor Committee, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    Letter with attached materials identifying affiliates of Lyndon LaRouche, press releases on several topics, October 1
  - Jobs with Justice, 1987-1993 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    Letter to Mazur from ACTWU president Jack Sheinkman re initial organization of Jobs with Justice campaign to educate public on trade union issues, inviting him to attend planning meeting for rally on Wall Street against corporate greed, September 28, 1987; letter to Mazur from Morton Bahr, president, Communication Workers of America (CWA), and Howard Samuel, president, AFL-CIO Industrial Union Department, updating him on first year of Jobs with Justice campaign, noting plans for 1988, anticipated expenditures, December 7, 1987; transcript, telephone news conference, August 16, 1988, with cover memos to Mazur and others; United Mine Workers Journal featuring Jobs with Justice rally, May 1988; guidelines, newsletter, and press release re Labor Day activities, 1988; letter from CWA re rally in support of newly organized Potomac Graphics workers, in New York, June 22, 1989; memo re hiring paid staff coordinator, September 1992; NLRB Action newspaper clippings, May 28, 1993
  - Jobs with Justice, Health Care Campaign, 1990-1993 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    See also Speeches – Jobs with Justice Health Care Campaign 1993 Flyers, instruction sheets, and sample press releases for Jobs with Justice Health Care Action Day, 1990; newsletter re Jobs with Justice National Health Care Action Week, 1991; notes re crucial role of New York area unions, New York rally kickoff of National Health Care Action Week, May 29 (1991?) meeting agenda, health care as Jobs with Justice #1 issue; memo re conference on universal health care, December 2, 1993; statement by Mazur at Jobs with Justice Health Care Conference, December 10, 1993; related correspondence
  - Job Net Referral System, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    Memo to Mazur from ILGWU exec asst James Parrott re union's JobNet job counseling and referral procedures; agenda for counselor training session
  - Kamber Group, 1986-1994 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    Proposal to ILGWU for public relations services, with descriptive material re firm, 1986; letter from Victor Kamber to president of International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) re hiring union labor, June 20, 1989; memo to Mazur from ILGWU vp Susan Cowell re Kamber suggestions for collaborating with ACTWU, March 31, 1986; "Modern Day Snake Oil: Term Limitations & Why They Must Be Defeated," a report by the Kamber Group, October 1991; Statement of George E. McDonald, President of the Allied Printing Trades Council of Greater New York, January 23, 1990; press release, "Unions on the Move to Save Jobs – And the Daily News," January 23, 1990; letter to Mazur from Victor Kamber offering assistance with boycott of Leslie Fay, June 24, 1994
  - Kennedy, John F., 1960-1963 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    Presidential inauguration program, January 20, 1961; issue of ILGWU Justice, re assassination, December 1, 1963; issue of ILGWU Spanish-language Justicia, re campaign, November 1960; memorial program for Kennedy and Herbert H. Lehman
  - Klein, Adam (Klein and Company), 1992-1993 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    See also ILGWU (UNITE) – Merger – GEB Adam Klein Study 7/20/92 and 2/7/93; see also National Committee for Labor Israel Outline of goals and detailed agenda for ILGWU Special General Executive Board Meeting on ILGWU's Strategic Direction, July 20 – 22, 1992, faxed by Klein; outline of remarks by Mazur for GEB Executive Session, July 20-22, 1992, summarizing convention, with memo from James Parrott, July 17, 1992; confidential memo to Mazur from Parrott re internal factions, preparation for February GEB Executive Session, January 20, 1992; letter of reference for Klein to Confederation of Health Service Employees, England, October 16, 1992; letter to Klein from ILGWU general secretary-treasurer Irwin Solomon expressing dismay over his having missed a strategic planning meeting, asserting that he should be responsible for cost of meeting and reimbursing union for most of uncompleted consulting project, February 12, 1993
  - Koch, Ed (NYC Mayor), 1985-1989 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    See also NYC – Industrial Loft Advisory Council; NYC – Commercial Rent Control; NYC 1984-1986 Outline for Manager's Meeting, March 8, 1989, listing reasons for ILGWU support of Dinkins candidacy over Koch; Statement by Theodore W. Kheel on Why I've Joined "Democrats for Guiliani If Koch Wins the Democratic Primary," April 2, 1989; letter from Mazur to Mayor Koch protesting his failure to march in Labor Day parade, September 6, 1988; Testimony of Edward I. Koch Before the City Council Committee on Relation and Special Event [sic] re discrimination against undocumented immigrants, December 22, 1988, with cover letter to Mazur, February 3, 1989; letter from Mazur to Koch urging support for Intro. 1088-A, protecting the health of video display terminal (VDT) users, December 15, 1989; memo to Mazur from ILGWU exec asst James Parrott re Koch support for weaker, alternative commercial (retail-only) rent control bill, August 2, 1989, with attached clipping from Crain's New York Business; statement by Koch against commercial rent control, May 7, 1985; statement from the garment industry on Mayor Koch's proposed commission to study commercial rent control, May 9, 1985; newspaper clipping from Daily News
  - Koret, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    Memorandum to Mazur from Mattie Jackson re import proposal, July 23, 1985; proposed language changes to agreement re imports
  - Labor, U.S. Department of, 1994-1995 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    Remarks by Labor Secretary Robert Reich, "The Revolt of the Anxious Class," to the Democratic Leadership Council, November 22, 1994; letters from the NYS Department of Labor thanking ILGWU associate director of research Walter Mankoff for serving on Minimum Wage Advisory Panel, September – December 1994; report to Mazur and Susan Cowell re Reich press briefing, September 14, 1994; letters to Mazur from U.S. Dept. of Labor re rulemaking changes re running for union office
  - Labor Advisory Committee for Trade Negotiations, 1988-1992 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    See also AFL-CIO Trade – Labor Advisory Committee for Trade Negotiations 1992-1998 Letter from U.S. Secretary of Labor Elizabeth Dole and U.S. Trade Representative Carla Hills inviting Mazur to serve on the Labor Advisory Committee for Trade Negotiations and Trade Policy, providing advice to the U.S. Trade Representative and the Secretary of Labor on international trade negotiations and U.S. trade policy, August 23, 1990, with attached description of subcommittee structure of Labor Advisory Committee; agenda for meeting of September 14, 1988, with cover letter to Mazur re attached memo "for official use only," outlining the status of the Uruguay Round of Trade Negotiations, and press releases, "Fact Sheet" from White House promoting the Omnibus Trade and Competitiveness Act of 1988, and remarks of President Reagan at signing of the bill, August 23, 1988; background material on oilseed production issues, U.S. – European Community Agreement on Agriculture and the Uruguay Round, November 24, 1992; memo to Mazur from ILGWU vp Susan Cowell re strategic approaches to union's trade position under the Clinton administration, November 12, 1992
  - Labor Committee for Pacific Affairs, 1983-1984 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    See also Labor Desk – United States Youth Council 1984 Minutes of inaugural meeting of trade union leaders from Australia, New Zealand, Fiji, Papua New Guinea, and the U.S.; confidential report of planning team, 1983; Regional Agenda, report by Michael Easson, ACTU Delegate to the Asian and Pacific Workers' Education ILO Seminar on the Social and Economic Services of Trade Unions, 1983; Process, official newsletter of the New Zealand Food Processing and Chemical Workers Union, September 1983; Australian Foreign Affairs Record, August 1983; correspondence; newspaper clippings
  - Labor Day Parade, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Memo to Mazur and others reporting on local Labor Day activities at West Invitations to Mazur to attend breakfast, march as member of honor guard in Labor Day Parade, July 12 and 23, 1993; press release by New York City Central Labor Council re Labor Day Parade, August 1993
  - Labor Day Parade, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Memo from New York City Central Labor Council re 1990 theme, Decent and Affordable Health Care for All, with line of march of participating unions, July 25, 1990; News from the UAW press release, with president Owen Bieber's Labor Day message, August 24, 1990; 13-page transcript of AFL-CIO president Lane Kirkland's Labor Day Conversation with Reporters, August 23, 1990
  - Labor Day Parade, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Clipping, front page of IBEW Electrical Union World, "Labor Day Parade: Jay Mazur Grand Marshal," with list of participating Local 3 divisions, August 15, 1988, and clipping covering event, September 21; front page of New York Observer with photo of Chinatown marchers in ILGWU T-shirts, September 12, 1988; sample of parade poster, with letter from official printer soliciting orders, July 14; invitation from New York City Central Labor Council to Mayor Ed Koch to join officials at parade, with reply declining invitation, August 18 and 22; Daily News press clipping re hostile reception for Ed Koch at West Indian Day (local Labor Day) parade in Brooklyn, September 6; letter from Gov. Michael Dukakis's presidential campaign office declining invitation, August 24; lists of labor and political officials at Labor Day Breakfast, September 8; Mazur speech at breakfast; list of scheduled dates and times of Labor Day commercial broadcasts, with thanks to those who contributed, August 23, 1988; memos from Mazur to New York City locals noting contribution expected from each to offset ILGWU expenses, November 9, 1988; list of contributions by unions for radio ad campaign, August 31; memo to Mazur re planning outline; revised schedule for planning meeting, July 12; list of line of march of participating unions, August 2; memo, press release, and related materials re Jobs with Justice Labor Day activities, August 23; routine correspondence
  - Labor Day Activities, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Memo to Mazur re Dinkins campaign update, July 21, 1989, and Labor Rally for David Dinkins scheduled for September 6, 1989; memo re plans for Housing Now National March on Washington scheduled for October 7, 1989, noting plans to participate in Labor Day Parade
  - Labor Day, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    Column by Mazur for Justice re new initiatives to increase union strength, including Associate Membership, for members who lose their jobs or whose shops have been unable to get a union contract
  - Labor Day Parade, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    Speech by Mazur reciting anti-labor actions by major employers across the country, July 26
  - Labor Day Parade, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    Financial records; list of slogans
  - Labor Day Parade, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    Agenda of activities; letter from Mazur suggesting new approach; related correspondence; newspaper clippings
  - Labor Day Parade, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    Memo to Mazur from ILGWU vp Susan Cowell re need to draw more crowds as spectators at Labor Day parades, September 23, 1983; letter to Mazur from parade coordinator, saying that parade was resounding success, September 8; minutes of national advisory committee meeting; outline of video recording of parade by Allen Tobias, Creative Developments; list of coordinators; related correspondence; financial records
  - Labor Desk, United States Youth Council (USYC), 1985 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    See also International Labor Program, Georgetown University 1983-1985; see also Labor Committee for Pacific Affairs 1983-1984 International organization supporting democratic labor unions; correspondence
  - Labor Desk, United States Youth Council (USYC), 1984 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    Advisory Committee minutes, correspondence
  - Labor Desk, United States Youth Council (USYC), Executive Committee, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    Talking points for meeting of February 5; meeting agendas and minutes; correspondence
  - Labor Law for Law Enforcement Officers, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    Letter from Mazur to NYS Attorney General Robert Abrams calling his attention to a publication created by the Delaware attorney general for distribution to law enforcement officers called to the scene of labor disputes, encouraging neutrality, August 30, 1990 (booklet not included)
  - Labor Law Reform, 1993-1994 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    see also Dunlop, John; see also Speeches – Donahue – Dunlop Commission Executive summary of report by AFL-CIO Industrial Union Department (IUD), "Democracy on the Job: America's Path to a Just, High Skill, High Wage Economy: An Agenda for Labor Law Reform"; draft of full report for final review, with cover letter from Richard Trumka and Elmer Chatak, August 19, 1993; draft of memo to Tom Donahue from Mazur, expressing concern over weakening section 8 (a) 12 of NLRA (prohibition against company-dominated unions), June 28, 1993; long letter from Mazur to John Dunlop, chair, Commission on the Future of Worker-Management Relations ("Dunlop Commission") re nature of jobber-contractor relationship, outsourcing in garment industry as technique for escaping responsibility for working conditions, April 29, 1994; memo to Mazur from Carl Proper (former ILG exec asst and director of Council for American Fashion, CAF) re IUD report, noting areas in need of strengthening, need to reverse imbalance of power, need for strong unions to maintain middle class and prevent reproduction of Third World economic and political conditions here, commenting on reaction of Dunlop to Mazur's suggestions, listing specific suggestions from other ILGWU sources, February 18, 1994; long letter from ILGWU assistant president Gus Tyler to Paula Voos, Department of Economics, University of Wisconsin, re role of commission, role of organized labor in maintaining standard of living "of that larger union called the United States," March 11, 1994; memo to Mazur from ILGWU general counsel Max Zimny re labor law reform (revised), October 12, 1992; memo from Mazur to IUD president Elmer Chatak outlining ILGWU recommendations for IUD consideration re NLRB reform, December 15, 1992; report of the first meeting of the Dunlop Commission, with cover memo to the AFL-CIO Committee on the Evolution of Work, June 8, 1993; report of the staff working groups on Organizing and Collective Bargaining to the AFL-CIO Committee on the Evolution of Work, May 18, 1993; recommendations of the AFL-CIO to the Commission on the Future of Worker Management relations: "Changes needed in the National Labor Relations Act and related laws," September 8, 1994
  - Labor Law Reform, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    Letter to AFL-CIO president Lane Kirkland from the president of the United Food & Commercial Workers International Union, urging that labor speak with one voice in advocating for reforms under the new Clinton administration, warning against claiming a mandate, acting too quickly, instead establishing nonpartisan commission of labor, management, and the public to study possible changes in labor law, December 8, 1992; memo to Mazur from ILGWU general counsel Max Zimny in advance of his chairing AFL-CIO panel on Labor Law Reform, outlining critical issues requiring legislative action, need to strengthen NLRA's remedies, expedite procedures, October 12, 1992; text of Mazur address to AFL-CIO Industrial Union Department Panel on Labor Law, "Restoring the Historic Balance," November 13, 1992; memo to Mazur reporting on meetings attended at AFL-CIO forums re labor law reform, noting specific legislative priorities, November 6, 1992; memo from Richard Trumka, president, United Mine Workers, re his appointment to chair AFL-CIO ad hoc Committee on Labor Law Reform and Organizing, noting strike replacement, legislative changes in NLRA and NLRB, highest priorities, asking for suggestions from affiliates, November 16, 1992; faxed memo from ILGWU Legal Dept. to AFL-CIO Industrial Union Department proposing labor law reforms, December 11; list of members of ad hoc Committee on Organizing and Labor Law reform; memo to Mazur from ILGWU vp and legislative director Evelyn Dubrow reporting on meeting of ad hoc committee, December 9, with agenda; Administrative Changes in the NLRB Proposed by the National Organizing NLRB Subcommittee of the AFL-CIO, February 24, 1992; Summary of Proposals Made by the AFL-CIO's Subcommittee on the NLRB, December 7, 1992; text of remarks by Prof. Ray Marshall of the University of Texas at Austin, former Secretary of Labor, re areas that need strengthening in the National Labor Relations Act
  - Labor-Management Committees, 1990-1994 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    see also Council for American Fashion (CAF) Memo to Mazur outlining steps for the establishment of proposed Local 23-25/Greater Blouse Labor Management Committee, July 12, 1994; Apparel Industry Magazine article describing Needle Trades Action Project (NTAP) in Massachusetts, Garment Industry Development Committee (GIDC) in New York, and other labor-management committees and development authorities, April 1991; Remarks of AFL-CIO President Lane Kirkland to the Ohio Regional Conference on Labor-Management Cooperation, September 6, 1990; "The Union's Call for Cooperation," by Jay Mazur, re GIDC, CAF, and other labor-management committees, reprinted from Bobbin, 1990; memo to Mazur from exec asst James Parrott discussing purpose of meetings between area labor-management committees (CAF, GIDC, NTAP), September 17, 1990
  - South Africa, Coplyn, John, 1994 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    Outline and speech by Mazur welcoming visitors from South Africa, discussing need for labor solidarity and social safety net in the years following the first multiracial elections, January 11- 12, 1994; agenda for meeting
  - South Africa, CUNY Conference on Labor Management Relations in South Africa, October 13, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    Letters to Mazur discussing agenda; letter to president of National Union of Mine Workers, September 9, 1988; list of participants
  - South Africa, 1988-1991 (Box 21, Folder 3)